<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>DGLW</title>
 <link href="http://www.dglw.nethttp://www.dglw.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.dglw.nethttp://www.dglw.net/"/>
 <updated>2015-07-08T13:04:21-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.dglw.net</id>
 <author>
   <name>Mark Otto</name>
   <email>markdotto@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Welcome!</title>
   <link href="http://www.dglw.net/2015/07/05/welcome/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.dglw.nethttp://www.dglw.net/2015/07/05/welcome</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This site has been updated to utilize &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/poole&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon&quot;&gt;Lanyon&lt;/a&gt; theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website will serve as a comprehensive place for my thoughts on all things professional to leisure.  Topics of professional interest include application development, business intelligence (BI), and digital project management.  Personal interests include snowboarding, bass playing, beer making, and following the Philadelphia sports teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;david-wolf&quot;&gt;_David Wolf&lt;/h3&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ransomware and the case for backups</title>
   <link href="http://www.dglw.net/2015/06/28/ransomware/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.dglw.nethttp://www.dglw.net/2015/06/28/ransomware</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a lot of my friends, I have become the resident IT expert for my family.  This means I may get called upon to handle all technical requests, from accessing email to deciphering the dreaded Windows blue-screen-of-death.  However, in my latest attempt to address my Mother’s concern that something was “very wrong with the computer this time,” remoting into the machine wasn’t an option.  So I took a drive to visit my parents and see what the problem was, and on the desktop background was a glaring message that read something of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://securityaffairs.co/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Critroni-ransomware-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents had become victims of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ransomware&quot;&gt;Ransomware&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  This can happen by generally (a) downloading a malicious package via an untrusted but well-disguised email, or (b) through an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eweek.com/security/slideshows/adobe-flash-vulnerabilities-ransomware-on-the-rise.html&quot;&gt;Adobe Flash vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;.  The later is not suprising to most techies, as flash has been known to have vulnerabilities, the latest being a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2015/7/8/8911077/adobe-flash-hacking-team-vulnerability&quot;&gt;huge vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; that may lead to remote root access to your machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When first run, the ransomware payload installs itself in the user profile folder, and adds a key to the registry that causes it to run on startup. It then attempts to contact one of several designated command and control servers; once connected, the server generates a 2048-bit RSA key pair, and sends the public key back to the infected computer.The payload then encrypts files across local hard drives and mapped network drives with the public key, and logs each file encrypted to a registry key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I pride myself in finding the optimum solution for whatever the problem is, but this was a whole new ballgame.  Quickly checking their documents folder, all of my parents files had been encrypted.  Every. single. one.  Scrubbing the registry had no effect, and I unaware of the steps that were being taken in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operation_Tovar&quot;&gt;Operation Tovar&lt;/a&gt; to disrupt the botnet that controlled the flavor of Ransomware that had infected my parent’s computer.  For once, I was defeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As there was no way I was going to pay the ransom, the only thing that saved my parent’s personal files was the auto-backup that I enabled when I first provisioned their Windows machine.  Re-installing the OS with a clean backup was the only option that allowed me to save my parents personal documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there are two morals to this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t open any email attachment in which you are not 100% sure of the sender identity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup an auto-backup service to protect your files in the case of cataclysmic failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Application Roundup&colon; Catch</title>
   <link href="http://www.dglw.net/2015/04/12/application-roundup-catch/"/>
   <updated>2015-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.dglw.nethttp://www.dglw.net/2015/04/12/application-roundup-catch</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Task/Idea Management &amp;amp; Note Taking: Catch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One great web &amp;amp; mobile application I generally suggest to those looking for a simple management interface for their notes, tasks, and ideas, is Catch. It’s easy to use and quick to update tasks and ideas as you move about your day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the plethora of task/idea management apps, Catch competes with the best when it comes to interface controls for users and seamless syncing. The mobile app navigation “fan” is quick to understand and navigate; You’ll soon wish that other apps were organized this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See if it works for you. You can find the free task management application at Catch or on your applicable app market for your smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Success, 7UP style</title>
   <link href="http://www.dglw.net/2015/02/12/success-7up-style/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.dglw.nethttp://www.dglw.net/2015/02/12/success-7up-style</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Article Roundup #1 today comes from the very popular financial journal, Forbes. I personally found the seven steps outlined in the article to be enlightening. Although I would be weary of the #1 step, “Marry a June Baby”, since emotional conflicts and mis-management can arise from doing business with friends and family, I love step #2, “Think Small”. For the same reasons I try to abide by the process followed by 37 Signals, as outlined in a previous blog post on their book Getting Real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/stevenberglas/2012/09/20/seven-7-steps-to-entrepreneurial-success/2/&quot;&gt;Forbes: Seven Steps to Entrepreneurial Success.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Application Roundup&colon; Trello</title>
   <link href="http://www.dglw.net/2015/02/05/application-roundup-trello/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.dglw.nethttp://www.dglw.net/2015/02/05/application-roundup-trello</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kanban Board: Trello&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are numerous task management applications out there to assist you in managing, executing, and completing your . They range from desktop to web-based applications, with many being open-source, standalone applications that you can deploy on your own server. I’ve had my share of experiences with deploying LAMP (read: PHP) project/task management applications with good results, including Trac, Project Pier, and Project HQ. The installs were relatively straight forward and should have you up and running in an hour or two. However, the downside is, you have to maintain this type of environment yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there’s something to be said about understanding the server install and deployment process for these open-sourced task management software, having an out-of-the-box, quick web solution is great for task management. Enter Trello. A web-based kanban board style interface, it allows the user quick access to task status. The drag and drop feature, although not new, is great when moving tasks from the que to “in action”. You can also color code your “epics”, which is nice for quick view on an updated task when being pressed on the conference call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See if it works for you. You can find the free task management software &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Revisiting Getting Real</title>
   <link href="http://www.dglw.net/2015/01/20/getting-real/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.dglw.nethttp://www.dglw.net/2015/01/20/getting-real</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Every year I revisit one of my favorite application and project management bibles, 37 Signal’s Getting Real. If you are interested in building successful web applications, new to the process, or just bettering yourself and your work, this is a great read for you. I can’t recommend enough how much I work on focusing on building more by building less, concentrating on those components that actually matter to the build process and disregarding those that don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a nominal fee (your email address), you can read 37 Signal’s Application Project Process at 37 Signals: Getting Real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also begun reading “Rework” by 37 Signals, A book on better managing a business in our present, hectic, and inefficient workplaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
